Vonnegut mss., 1941-2007 LMC 1860
Lilly Library
- VI. Additions
  - Writings - major works. (Box 26)
    - Happy Birthday, Wanda June. Revised ending for operatic versionplaybill for The Access Theater, New York City, opening night press kit for stage version directed by Robert Weide, Elephant Theater, Hollywood, CA, photocopies of reviews of various productions, February 14, 2006; Apr. 1, 2004; Oct. 26 to Dec. 9, 2001 (Box 26)
    - L'Histoire du Soldat. Revised libretto...prior to publication in the Paris Review, January 1998 (Box 26)
    - If God Were Alive Today. Preface only to unpublished novel, September 22, 2002 (Box 26)
    - A Man Without a Country. Typescript of preface; mock-up of book jacket (Box 26)
    - Mother Night. Preface to the American Edition in Russian, list of credits for staged reading, adapted and directed by Frances Miksits, Feb. 14, 1986 (Box 26)
    - Timequake. (Box 27)
      - Multiple drafts and portions of chapters, master copy and various printer's copies (Box 27)
      - Multiple drafts...cont., (9 folders) (Box 28)
      - Correspondence and other materials concerning the translation and Vonnegut's tour of Germany in 1998 (Box 28)
    - Welcome to the Monkey House. Mock-up of CD cover (Box 28)
    - Welcome to the Monkey House. Revised draft, with photocopy, for Playboy magazine, 1968 (Box 28)
  - Writings - articles, short stories, booklets, etc. (Box 28)
    Arranged alphabetically by title or subject. Mostly photocopies of typescripts with some original typescripts unless otherwise indicated
    - Al Hirschfeld, The Maker of Icons. For collection in book form of Hirschfeld drawings, June 1998 (Box 28)
    - The Art of Kurt Vonnegut: Catalog of Original Silkscreens, with Joe Petro III., 1997 (Box 28)
    - April in East Hampton. Catalogue copy for April Gornik Show at Glenn Horowitz Gallery in East Hampton, Summer, 1999 (Box 28)
    - Bernard Vonnegut: The Rainmaker (The New York Times Magazine, Jan. 4, 1998 (Box 28)
    - Can Writing be Taught? (New York Times, Apr. 28, 1999) (Box 28)
    - Enchanted IOUs. Portfolio produced with Joe Petro III. Layout and cover letter., 2001 (Box 28)
    - The End Is Near (In These Times, Oct. 29, 2004) (Box 28)
    - [Festschrift for Morgan Entrekin's birthday], Jan. 8, 2005 (Box 28)
    - God Bless You, Dr. Kevorkian. Reports on afterlife recorded for PBS station WNYC., Typescript of one report and printer's copy of compilation printed as premium for donation to the station (Box 28)
    - I am here to serve the people of the United States of America...[first line], June 16, 1988 (Box 28)
    - In-the-Bone Reading (unknown magazine, 1999) (Box 28)
    - In the Manner That Must Shame God Himself (Harpers, Nov. 1972) (Box 28)
    - [Interviews with]: Joel Bleifus for In These Times magazine, Joel Bleifus for Playboy magazine, Walter Miller for Essential Vonnegut - mockup of CD packaging and cover letter only; Eric Solstein, 2003; 2005; 1999 (Box 28)
    - Knowing What's Nice (In These Times, Nov. 17, 2003) (Box 28)
    - Kurt Vonnegut vs. the !&#*!@ (In These Times, Feb. 17, 2003) (Box 28)
    - The Lake (Architectural Digest, 1987) (Box 28)
    - Last Words for a Century (aka: Fuh-kar-wee Indians and the Christian Year (Playboy, 2000); Jan. 1999) (Box 28)
    - A Midsummer's Night Benefit, first sketch...for the book of a musical parody of "A Midsummer's Night Dream," by Shakespeare of course, January 9, 2000 (Box 28)
    - The old university town of Weimar,...[first line] (The Nation, March 12, 1998) (Box 28)
    - [Poetry]., Typescripts, photocopies of published poems, reprint (Box 28)
    - Preface. (unpublished, undated) (Box 28)
    - [Prefaces]. Bartlett's Words to Live By and Thornton Wilder's The Ides of March (Box 28)
    - Reunions (Forbes ASAP, Oct. 4, 1999) (Box 28)
    - Stormy Weather. Submitted to The New York Times op ed page, Nov. 3, 1998 (Box 28)
    - Strange Weather Lately (In These Times, June 9, 2003) (Box 28)
    - This has always been not only a racist society...[first line], undated (Box 28)
    - Vonnegut's Last Conversation with Kilgore Trout, October 1, 2004 (Box 28)
    - Zoology 101 (Forbes ASAP). For a collection of essays on biotechnology, Mar. 15, 1999 (Box 28)
    - Printed magazines, tear sheets and photocopies of articles by KV (Box 28)
    - Printed. Photocopies of columns by KV, from The Cornell Daily Sun, 1941-1943 (Box 33)
  - Writings - quotes (Box 28)
    - Includes blurbs on book jackets, group collected for a portfolio, copy for postcards., Printed, typescripts and photocopies (Box 28)
  - Writings - speeches and lectures. (Box 28)
    Mostly typescripts with some correspondence and other related materials.
    - The Imagination of the State. Panel discussion at International P.E.N. Congress in New York City, 1986, Jan. 17 (Box 28)
    - Tribute to Elsa Bonner, 1986, Feb. 11 (Box 28)
    - Florida State University, Tallahassee (see also: poster), 1997, Mar. 21 (Box 28)
    - Rice University, Houston, Texas, graduation address, 1998 (Box 28)
    - Agnes Scott College, Atlanta, Georgia, graduation address, 1999, May 15 (Box 28)
    - Faith Sale, memorial service remarks, 2000, Jan. 7 (Box 29)
    - Tribute to Joseph Heller, 2000, Apr. 4 (Box 29)
    - Shortridge HIgh School Class of 1940 reunion, Indianapolis, 2000, June 17 (Box 29)
    - Smith College, 2000, Sept. 5 (Box 29)
    - Indiana Civil Liberties Union, Indianapolis, 2000, Sept. 16 (Box 29)
    - Carl Sanburg Award, Chicago, 2001, Oct. 12 (Box 29)
    - Dag Hammarskjold Plaza, New York City. September 11 remembrance, 2001, Oct. 23 (Box 29)
    - Beekman School, New York City, graduation address, 2001, ca. June. (Box 29)
    - St. Marks on the Bowery, New York City. September 11 remembrance, 2002, Sept. 11 (Box 29)
    - Tribute to Donald Farber, 2002, Sept. 29 (Box 29)
    - Clemens lecture, 2003, Apr. 30 (Box 29)
    - Tribute to George Plimpton, 2003, Oct. 14 (Box 29)
    - "Listen." Recorded at DG Systems, NYC, 2003, Nov. 3 (Box 29)
    - Tribute to Jules Feiffer, 2004, Feb. 21 (Box 29)
    - Lehigh University, graduation address, 2004, May 24 (Box 29)
    - Eastern Washington University, Spokane, 2004, Apr. 17 (Box 29)
    - Ollie M. Lyon, Jr., memorial service remarks., 2005, Jan. 28 (Box 29)
    - Tribute to Dan Berrigan, 2006, June 10 (Box 29)
    - "The Family Business or Cosa Nostra"; tribute to Nelson Algren, undated. (Box 29)
  - Writings by Others (Box 29)
    - Blanchard, Duncan. The Lighter Side of a Life in Science (Box 29)
    - Buckman, Robert. What You Really Need to Know About Cancer., Photocopy of cover and dedication to KV (Box 29)
    - Davey, Lynn. Early Childhood Development: What Matters Most? (Box 29)
    - Herzog, Roman. Speech...Dresden on, 13 February 1995 (Box 29)
    - Kasper, Becky. A Letter to Vonnegut, Aug. 1999; (2 folders) (Box 29)
    - Nielson, Thomas. Caught in a Timequake: Time and History in the Fiction of Kurt Vonnegut. Thesis, Odense Universitet, 1998 (Box 29)
    - Reese, Preston. Dear Mr. Vonnegut., 1996 (Box 29)
    - Sigler, Sean D. (fifth grade teacher, Gardner Street School, Los Angeles, CA). How to Survive the Future: The Quotes of Kurt Vonnegut...With the Help from the kids of Room 21 (Gardner Street) School. (Box 29)
    - Szpek, Ervin, Jr. Ex-POWs of Slaughterhouse Five (newsletter)., 1997-1999; 2002 (Box 29)
    - Thom, James Alexander. A Major League Asterisk. Speech to the Indiana Civil Liberties Union, Oct. 10, 2003 (Box 29)
    - Weide, Robert B. The Morning After Mother Night. (Box 29)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 29)
    - Biographical. Photocopy of Alex Vonnegut journalphotocopy of letter to father, 1902-1903; May 29, 1945; Recounts experiences from his capture near Luxemburg on Dec. 19, 1944 to his recuperation, Le Havre P.O.W. repatriation camp; photocopy of newspaper article announcing KV as missing in action, Indianapolis Times, Jan. 15, 1945; etc. (2 folders) (Box 29)
    - Artifacts: Three buttons; two copies of sticker: "Rare Earth 'We could have saved it, but we were too darn cheap and lazy.--Kurt Vonnegut'; two coasters with drawings by KV (Box 29)
    - Family: (Box 29)
      - Krementz, Jill., emph: Something about the Author Autobiography Series (Box 29)
      - Prior, Nanette (daughter)., Two poems by NP; announcement of art show; catalog of paintings by husband Scott Prior; etc. (Box 29)
      - Vonnegut, Bernard., Writings by and about BV; memorial service program (Box 29)
      - Vonnegut, Edith., emph: Domestic Goddess; date: 2006;; date: 1997;; date: 1995 (Box 29)
      - Vonnegut, Lily., date: 2006 (Box 29)
      - Vonnegut, Mark., emph: The Eden Express (Box 29)
    - Inventory cards: Fortitude (2)Welcome to the Monkey House, 1967-1968; 1968 (Box 29)
    - Itineraries (Box 29)
    - Photographs: KV shaking President Bill Clinton's hand at White House State reception for President Vaclav HavelGold Medal for Drama Committee, KV, Arthur Miller, Edward Albee, Brendan Gill; KV at reunion of boyhood friends, Sept. 16, 1998; 12/4/97; July 10, 1999 (Box 29)
    - Printed: (Box 29)
      - Articles about KV, 1997-2007 (Box 29)
      - Reviews for various books, (7 folders) (Box 29)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 29)
    - VHS tapes: (Box 30)
      - Albion College, Apr. 18, 2002 (Box 30)
      - Mark Twain House, Apr. 30, 2003 (Box 30)
      - New Mexico University, Apr. 26, 2002 (Box 30)
      - Spokane, Apr. 17. 2004 (Box 30)
    - Artwork by KV: One original painting, five silkscreened paintings, one silkscreened quote (Box 32)
    - "I Don't Know What It Is About Hoosiers….", Silkscreen Print (Box 32)
    - Posters: (Box 32)
      - Joseph Heller, William Styron, Kurt Vonnegut - War Stories: Reality and Metaphor, A Colloquium...Florida State University, Tallahassee, Mar. 21, 1997 (Box 32)
      - One Book One City, Indianapolisposter and brochure, 2007 (Box 32)
    - Poster for The Year of Vonnegut Indianapolis, 2007 (Box 34)
- VII. Additions II
  - Writings - Major Works
    - Player Piano, (1952) (Box 35)
      - Handwritten notes (Box 35)
      - Typescript with handwritten corrections (Box 35)
      - Miscellaneous typescript pages with handwritten corrections (Box 35)
      - 5 typescripts to insert between chapters with handwritten corrections (Box 35)
      - Chapters I-XVIII typescripts with handwritten corrections, (approx. 236 pages) (3 folders) (Box 35)
      - Chapters I-XXXVIII typescript carbon copies with handwritten corrections, (approx. 405 pages) (4 folders) (Box 35)
      - Chapters XXV-XXIV typescript with handwritten corrections, (approx. 100 pages) (Box 35)
      - Setting copy with Vonnegut's handwritten corrections and copyeditor's notes, (4 folders) (Box 35)
      - Galley proofs with Vonnegut's handwritten corrections and publisher's memo (Box 35)
      - Screenplay typescript by Pressman Williams Enterprises Inc., 1969 (Box 35)
    - Sirens of Titan, (1959) (Box 35)
      - Handwritten notes by Vonnegut and other person (Box 35)
      - Novel summary typescript and early draft with annotations using earlier title, "Sirens of Triton" (Box 35)
      - Miscellaneous typescript pages with handwritten corrections (Box 35)
      - Chapter typescripts (Chapters 6, 7, 11, 12, 13, 14), (2 folders) (Box 35)
      - Typescript with handwritten corrections, (4 folders) (Box 36)
    - Mother Night, (1961) (Box 36)
      - Typescript with handwritten corrections using earlier title, "Spy Story", (approx. 20 pages) (Box 36)
      - Typescript using earlier title, "Nation of Two", (approx. 100 pages) (Box 36)
      - Typescript with handwritten corrections using earlier title, "Nation of Two", (approx. 200 pages) (3 folders) (Box 36)
      - Typescript carbon copy with handwritten corrections, copy 1, (approx. 230 pages) (2 folders) (Box 36)
      - Typescript carbon copy with handwritten corrections, copy 2, (approx. 230 pages) (2 folders) (Box 36)
    - Cat's Cradle, (1963) (Box 36)
      - Typescript with handwritten corrections using earlier title, "Ice-9" and a few miscellaneous pages, (approx. 30 pages) (Box 36)
      - Typescript with handwritten corrections using earlier title, "Ice-9", (approx. 70 pages) (Box 36)
      - Typescript carbon copy with handwritten corrections using earlier title, "Ice-9", (approx. 110 pages) (Box 36)
      - Typescript carbon copy with handwritten and taped-in typescript corrections using earlier title, "Ice-9", (approx. 70 pages) (Box 36)
      - Typescript carbon copy with handwritten corrections using earlier title, "Ice-9", (approx. 50 pages) (Box 36)
      - Miscellaneous pages, including notes, editor's queries, summaries, chapters and pages using earlier title, "Ice-9". Includes typescripts and manuscripts (Box 36)
      - Typescript (12 pages), miscellaneous pages, and handwritten notes (Box 37)
      - Photocopy of typescript, (approx. 35 pages) (Box 37)
      - Typescript with handwritten corrections, (approx. 70 pages) (Box 37)
      - Typescript with handwritten corrections, (approx. 180 pages) (2 folders) (Box 37)
      - Typescript with handwritten corrections, (approx. 280 pages) (3 folders) (Box 37)
      - Typescript carbon copy, (approx. 280 pages) (3 folders) (Box 37)
      - Setting copy with Vonnegut's handwritten corrections and copyeditor's handwritten notes and related materials, (4 folders) (Box 37)
      - Galley proofs with Vonnegut's handwritten corrections and copyeditor's handwritten notes (Box 37)
      - Dramatic adaption typescript drafts with handwritten corrections (Box 37)
    - God Bless You, Mr. Rosewater; or Pearls Before Swine, (1965) (Box 37)
      - Typescript with handwritten corrections using earlier title, "Some Sweet Beginnings", (approx. 15 pages) (Box 37)
      - Typescript and miscellaneous pages with handwritten corrections using earlier title, "The Rosewater Foundation", (approx. 45 pages) (Box 37)
      - Typescript with handwritten corrections using earlier title, "God Bless You, Mr. Rosewater; or The Volunteer", (approx. 47 pages) (Box 37)
      - Typescript carbon copy using earlier title, "God Bless You, Mr. Rosewater; or, The Volunteer" (approx. 50 pages) and typist's invoice (Box 38)
      - Typescript with handwritten corrections using earlier title, "God Bless You, Mr. Rosewater; or, The Volunteer.", Pages stapled together into 10 foot long ream (Box 38)
      - Typescript with handwritten corrections using earlier title, "Rosewater"., Pages stapled together into 4 foot long ream (Box 38)
      - Typescript with handwritten corrections using earlier title, "Rosewater"., Pages stapled together into 3 foot long ream (Box 38)
      - Typescript with handwritten corrections, (approx. 173 pages) (3 folders) (Box 38)
      - Typescript carbon copy with handwritten corrections, (approx. 300 pages) (3 folders) (Box 38)
      - Dramatic adaptation typescript draft and manuscript materials. (Box 38)
      - Dramatic adaptation typescript with handwritten corrections., Pages stapled together into 16 foot long ream (Box 38)
      - Dramatic adaptation typescript with handwritten corrections., Pages stapled together into 10 foot long ream (Box 38)
    - Breakfast of Champions "early versions (70 – 71)", (1973) (Box 38)
      - Chapter One typescript with handwritten corrections, (approx. 10 pages), 3 copies (Box 38)
      - Chapter One typescript with handwritten corrections (approx. 16 pages) and miscellaneous typescript pages (Box 38)
      - Typescript with handwritten corrections using earlier title, "Breakfast of Champions; or Goodbye Blue Monday", (approx. 95 pages) (2 folders) (Box 38)
      - Miscellaneous typescript pages (Box 38)
      - Film adaptation typescript pages with handwritten corrections (Box 38)
  - Writings - Short fiction, plays and screenplays (Box 38)
    - "The Rover Boys in the American Southwest, August 1939" short story typescript with handwritten corrections (Box 38)
    - Fragments from binder 1, including materials for: dramatic adaptation of God Bless You, Mr. Rosewater, short fictions "Guardian of the Person" and "While the Wine is Sweet.", Typescripts, manuscripts, and sketches (2 folders) (Box 38)
    - Fragments from binder 2, including materials for:Cat's Cradle, Mother Night, and dramatic adaptation of God Bless you Mr. Rosewater. (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Typescripts, manuscripts and sketches (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Uncle Upstairs play typescript (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Heidi Again play typescript (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Daedalus play typescript materials and manuscript materials (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - "Carbons for Television Synopses, Volume One", including television synopses of Slice of Life, Player Piano, Hoosier Symphony, Money Talks, Slaughterhouse Five, and The Bagman (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Realia (Oversize (No Box))
    - Trunk that housed Kurt Vonnegut's manuscripts, from Edie Vonnegut's home (Oversize (No Box))